Hui Ye

Research Focus

My research interests lie in the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and Computer Graphics (CG). Specifically, my main research focus is on exploring novel mobile AR prototyping tools and techniques for 3D contents and interactions.

Education

• City University of Hong Kong (CityU)

Sep 2017-Aug 2022

Ph.D. in Creative Media Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

Thesis: 3D Content and Interaction Prototyping with Mobile Augmented Reality

• University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

Sep 2012-June 2016

B.A. in Communication

Minor in Computer Science and Technology

Experience

• RGC Postdoctoral Fellow, City University of Hong Kong

Sep 2022-Current

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

• Research Assistant, City University of Hong Kong

Sep 2021-Aug 2022

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

• Visiting Ph.D. student, Tsinghua University

Dec 2019-Apr 2020

Institute of HCI and Media Integration Advisors: Dr. Chun Yu and Prof. Hongbo Fu

o City University of Hong Kong

Sep-Dec 2014

Exchange student

Publications

- **Hui Ye** and Hongbo Fu. 2022. ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces. In *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI 2022).
- **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan, and Hongbo Fu. 2021. 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)*.
- Hui Ye, Kin Chung Kwan (joint first author), Wanchao Su, and Hongbo Fu. 2020. ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures. In ACM Transactions on Graphics (Special Issue of ACM SIGGRAPH 2020).
- Wanchao Su, Hui Ye, Shuyu Chen, Lin Gao, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. DrawingInStyles: Portrait Image Generation and Editing with Spatially Conditioned StyleGAN. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization* and Computer Graphics (TVCG). Accepted for publication.
- Xuanyu Wang, Hui Ye, Christian Sandor, Weizhan Zhang, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. Predict-and-Drive: Avatar Motion Adaption in Room-Scale Augmented Reality Telepresence with Heterogeneous Spaces. In IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG): Special Issue for IEEE ISMAR 2022. Accepted for publication.

- Yanxiang Zhang and **Hui Ye**. 2016. Time-Based Nonlinear Interactive Player. In *International Conference on Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality and Computer Graphics*. Springer, Cham.
- Yanxiang Zhang, Yun Zhu, **Hui Ye**. 2015. The Design of an Augmented Reality Based Rigid Body Motion Experiment System. In *Applied Mechanics and Materials*. Trans Tech Publications Ltd.

Selected Honors & Awards

| RGC Postdoctoral Fellowship | 2022 |
|---|----------------------------------|
| Outstanding Academic Performance Award of CityU | 2021 |
| Shidi CAD&CG Excellent Student Award | 2021 |
| Research Tuition Scholarship of CityU | 2020 |
| o Guo Moruo Scholarship (Top 2%, Highest Honor for USTC Undergraduates) | 2016 |
| o Merit Graduate of Anhui Province & USTC (Top 3%) | 2016 |
| • Certificate of Honorary Rank of USTC (Top 5%) | 2016 |
| Outstanding Thesis of USTC | 2016 |
| Sun Bin Leadership Scholarship of USTC | 2014 |
| Aegon-Industrial Responsibility Scholarship of USTC | 2014 |
| Outstanding Instructor in "Science and Technology Week" of USTC | 2013-15 |
| o Gold Award of Excellent Student Scholarship of USTC (Top 5%) | 2013 |
| Outstanding Young Volunteer of USTC | 2013 |
| Talks | |
| The Road from Communication to Computer Graphics Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&CG 2022+2023 | Aug 2022 |
| ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022 | May 2022 |
| Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions Invited Speaker, EAA Youth Academic Forum, Tianjin Fine Arts Institute | Apr 2022 |
| Exploring Novel Mobile AR Prototyping Techniques and Tools for 3D Contents and Interactions SIGGRAPH Thesis Fast Forward | Dec 2021 |
| ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures | |
| Invited Speaker, Graphics And Mixed Environment Symposium (GAMES) Invited Speaker, SCM ACIM Colloquium, CityU Conference Paper Presenter, SIGGRAPH 2020 | Sep 2021 Oct 2020 Aug 2020 |
| 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR Invited Speaker, IEEE VR 2021 | Mar 2021 |
| In-situ 3D Content Creation in Mobile AR Invited Speaker, Affiliated Forum on Human, Technology and Future of IWHEC 2021 | Mar 2021 |
| Too shing Eymonian as | |

Teaching Experience

| o Teaching Assistant, CityU SM1103A Introduction to Media Computing | 2018 & 19 Fall |
|--|----------------|
| Teaching Assistant, CityU SM2716 Physical Computing & Tangible Media | 2018 Spring |

Professional Service

- Paper Review: CHI 2023 & 2022 & 2020, SIGGRAPH Asia 2022, UIST 2022, MobileHCI 2022, TVCG 2022, IEEE VR 2021, IEEE AIVR 2021, PG 2020
- o Competition Jury: Jury Member of CHI 2022 Student Research Competition
- Student Helper: PG 2018

Skills

- **Programming Language**: C#, Swift, Python, HTML
- o Graphics interface: OpenCV, QT
- o Application Tools: iOS App, ARKit, HoloLens App, Mixed Reality Toolkit
- o Hardware: HoloLens, Arduino, Motion Capture

Last updated on October 27, 2022